<?xml version="1.0"?>
<gameList>
	<game id="88055" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Donkey Kong (Multi Screen).mgw</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong (multi Screen)</name>
		<desc>Mario doit atteindre le sommet de la structure et activer un levier qui va mettre une grue à sa portée.
Ensuite, il doit sauter de la grue et démolir peu à peu la structure sur laquelle Donkey Kong se trouve afin de sauver Pauline.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong (Multi Screen)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong (Multi Screen)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong (Multi Screen)-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19820603T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="99461" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Donkey Kong Circus (Panorama).mgw</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong Circus</name>
		<desc>Donkey Kong jongle avec des ananas tout en étant en équilibrant sur un baril.
Attrapez les ananas, mais méfiez-vous des boules de feu.
Des vies sont perdues, si un ananas tombe sur le sol ou si Donkey Kong touche une boule de feu.
Quand toutes les vies sont utilisées le jeu se termine.
Vous gagnez 1 point pour chaque ananas rattrapé.
Le plus gros score affichable est 999.
Au bout de 300 points tous les accidents sont annulés.
Si il n'y a pas eut de vie de perdue au bout de 300 points, le jeu passe en "Chance-Time": tous les points sont attribués au double de la valeur (2 points par ananas rattrapé) jusqu'à ce que vous perdiez une vie.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong Circus (Panorama)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong Circus (Panorama)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong Circus (Panorama)-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19840906T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre />
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88056" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Donkey Kong II (Multi Screen).mgw</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong 2</name>
		<desc>La suite de la célèbre histoire de Donkey Kong.
Mario à enchaîné Donkey Kong, vous devez le délivrer.
Déplacez Donkey Kong junior jusqu'à l'endroit où son papa est retenu prisonnier.
Sur le chemin récupéré la clé d'un des cadenas et faite attention aux alligators, étincelles, oiseaux.

Lorsque Donkey Kong junior atteint l'écran supérieur avec la clé, il doit choisir quel cadenas ouvrir.
Une fois prés du verrou en haut de la chaine appuyez sur la touche "plus" pour l'ouvrir</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong II (Multi Screen)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong II (Multi Screen)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong II (Multi Screen)-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830307T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88098" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Donkey Kong Jr (Panorama).mgw</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong Jr. (panorama Screen)</name>
		<desc>Donkey Kong a été capturé par Mario.
Donkey Kong Jr. doit le libérer de ses chaînes.
Sur le chemin Donkey Kong Jr. est  attaqué par des oiseaux.
Il utilise des parapluies et des ballons pour sauter depuis les hauteurs, et  atteindre les cadenas.
Quand il ouvre les 4 cadenas, Donkey Kong est libre.
Chaque fois qu'il ouvre une serrure, Donkey Kong Jr. doit recommencer du début pour récupérer la clé, puis repart libérer son père.
Au bout de trois essaies, le jeu se termine.
Le plus gros score affichable est de 999 points.
Au bout de 999 points marqué le jeux reprend de zéro à une vitesse plus élevée.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong Jr (Panorama)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong Jr (Panorama)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkjrp.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>01010101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="99462" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Egg.mgw</path>
		<name>Egg</name>
		<desc>Les poulets pondent des oeufs.
Contrôlez le loup afin qu'il les attrape dans son chapeau.
Quand le loup laisse tomber un oeuf, vous ne marquez pas de point.
Le coq apparaît/disparaît toutes les cinq secondes.
Lorsque le coq apparaît alors que l'oeuf tombe, vous perdez un essai.
Au bout de trois essai, le jeu se termine.
Vous gagnez 1 point par oeuf dans le chapeau.
A 200 et 500 points, une musique retentit et vous regagnez les essais perdus.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Egg-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Egg-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Egg-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19811009T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre />
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88072" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Lifeboat (Multi Screen).mgw</path>
		<name>Lifeboat</name>
		<desc>Un incendie éclate sur un bateau de luxe; Les passagers sautent du navire. Il faut mettre l'embarcation de sauvetage en position pour attraper les passagers. Chaque embarcation de sauvetage peut accueillir jusqu'à quatre passagers. Il ya un rivage à gauche et à droite de l'écran. Lorsqu'un canot de sauvetage atteint la rive, les passagers se déchargent automatiquement. 1 point par personne. 1 point par personne déchargé au rivage. Le score maximum affiché est de 999. A 300 points, les sons de fanfare et tous les misses sont annulés; S'il n'y a pas de points manqués lorsque 300 points sont atteints, le jeu se déroule dans «Chance-Time»: le score clignote et tous les points sont attribués à la double valeur (2 points par passager pris ou déchargé au rivage)</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Lifeboat (Multi Screen)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Lifeboat (Multi Screen)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Lifeboat (Multi Screen)-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19831016T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88073" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Mario Bros (Multi Screen).mgw</path>
		<name>Mario Bros.</name>
		<desc>Mario est de retour en action avec son frère Luigi, travaillant dans une usine d'embouteillage, le chargement des caisses sur un tapis roulant. Le convoyeur transporte les caisses pour le chargement sur les camions. Exploite Mario et Luigi en haut et en bas des échelles afin d'obtenir des caisses. Quand une caisses est abandonné, le contremaître se met en colère et un misse est marqué. Trois misses et le jeu est terminé .  1 point par carton chargé sur un convoyeur. 10 points par camion chargé de 8 caisses. À 300 points fanfare sonne et tous les misses sont annulés; S'il n'y a pas de manquer quand 300 points sont atteints, le jeu entre dans "CHANCE TIME". Score clignote et tous les points sont attribués à la double valeur jusqu'à ce que l'erreur soit faite. Le score maximum affiché est de 999 points.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Mario Bros (Multi Screen)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Mario Bros (Multi Screen)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Mario Bros (Multi Screen)-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>01010101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88074" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Mario's Bombs Away (Panorama).mgw</path>
		<name>Mario's Bombs Away</name>
		<desc>Mario est dans la jungle et se bat contre une armée ennemie.nnLe but est de déposer cinq bombes sur le côté droit de la jungle. Lorsque les cinq bombes sont en place, elles explosent et l'armée ennemie est vaincue.nnLes ennemis essaient d'allumer la bombe. Soulevez / baissez la bombe pour la garder en sécurité.nnSi les torches de l'ennemi atteignent la bombe, tous les progrès (les bombes déjà placées) sont perdus.nnTrois échecs et le jeu se termine.nnVous obtenez 1 point quand Mario fait un pas en avant, 5 points quand Mario livre une bombe, 10 points lorsque Mario livre la cinquième bombe.nnUne fanfare retentit à 300 points et toutes les erreurs sont annulées - s'il n'y a pas eu d'erreur alors le jeu entre en "Chance-Time", le marqueur clignote et tous les points attribués ont une valeur double jusqu'à ce qu'une faute soit commise.nnLe score maximum affiché est de 999 points.nnÀ 999 points, le score est réinitialisé et la partie reprend (à une vitesse supérieure).</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Mario's Bombs Away (Panorama)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Mario's Bombs Away (Panorama)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Mario's Bombs Away (Panorama)-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>01010101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88075" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Mickey Mouse (Panorama).mgw</path>
		<name>Mickey Mouse (panorama Screen)</name>
		<desc>Mickey Mouse effectue des acrobaties avec des baguettes tout en se balançant sur une balle dans un cirque. Donald Duck surveille les exploits. Déplacez Mickey à gauche et à droite pour attraper les baguettes, mais méfiez-vous des torches enflammées. Une erreur est enregistrée lorsque Mickey ne parvient pas à attraper une baguette ou lorsqu'il attrape une torche enflammée. Trois erreurs et le jeu se termine. 1 point est donné pour chaque baguette attrapée. Le score maximum affiché est de 999. À 300 points, la fanfare retentit et toutes les erreurs sont annulées. S'il n'y a pas eu d'erreur, le jeu passe en "Chance-Time", tous les points attribués ont une valeur double jusqu'à la première erreur.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Mickey Mouse (Panorama)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Mickey Mouse (Panorama)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mmousep.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>01010101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88076" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Mickey Mouse (Wide Screen).mgw</path>
		<name>Mickey Mouse (wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Les poules pondent des oeufs. Contrôle Mickey Mouse de sorte qu'il les attrape dans son panier. Quand Mickey Mouse laisse tomber un oeuf, un miss est marqué. Minnie apparaît / disparaît toutes les cinq secondes. Lorsque Minnie apparaît alors que l'oeuf tombe, la moitié de miss est marquée (la marque manquante clignote). Trois miss complets et le jeu est terminé. 1 point par oeuf pris. À 200 et 500 points, s'il y a un ou plusieurs ratés, les sons de fanfare et tous les miss sont annulés. Le score maximum affiché est de 999 points.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Mickey Mouse (Wide Screen)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Mickey Mouse (Wide Screen)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Mickey Mouse (Wide Screen)-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19811009T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88082" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Parachute.mgw</path>
		<name>Parachute</name>
		<desc>Un hélicoptère largue des parachutistes. Le joueur, qui contrôle un rameur dans une barque grâce aux 2 boutons (gauche et droite), doit rattraper le parachutiste avant qu'il ne tombe à l'eau et se fasse dévorer par les requins.
Chaque parachutiste récupéré vaut 1 point mais chaque parachutiste qui va à la mer donne un malus matérialisé par une tête de requin. Au bout de 3 malus, la partie est terminée. Si le joueur atteint 200 points puis 500 points, les malus sont supprimés et une petite musique retenti.
Il existe 2 type de jeu (type A et type B). La seule différence du jeu en type B est que les parachutistes peuvent ou non rester accrochés à un palmier et se décrochent de façon aléatoire ce qui augmente la difficulté du jeu.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Parachute-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Parachute-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Parachute-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19810619T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88088" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Snoopy (Panorama).mgw</path>
		<name>Snoopy (panorama Screen)</name>
		<desc>Shroeder joue de son piano. Les notes volent dans l'air jusqu'à l'endroit où Woodstock dort. Orienter Snoopy à gauche et à droite pour frapper les notes avec son marteau afin que Woodstock puisse dormir en paix. Si une note arrive jusqu'à lui, une erreur se produit. Trois erreurs et la partie est terminée. Jeu A: 3 lignes de notes. Jeu B: 4 lignes de notes. 1 point pour chaque note abattue. A 300 points, une musique est jouée et toutes les erreurs sont annulées. S'il n'y a pas eu d'erreur quand les 300 points sont atteints, le jeu passe en "Chance-Time", le score clignote et tous les points ont une valeur double jusqu'à ce qu'une erreur soit commise. Le score affichable maximum est de 999 points. À 999 points, le score est réinitialisé et le jeu recommence (à une vitesse supérieure).</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Snoopy (Panorama)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Snoopy (Panorama)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Snoopy (Panorama)-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>01010101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88090" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Snoopy Tennis.mgw</path>
		<name>Snoopy Tennis</name>
		<desc>Charlie Brown et Snoopy jouent au tennis. Snoopy doit grimper à l'arbre pour recevoir le service de Charlie Brown. Lucy ne cesse d intercepte la balle de snoopy et de la renvoie . Presser lorsque la balle est juste en face du visage Snoopy. Lorsque Snoopy bascule et manque, il ne peut pas bouger jusqu'à ce que sa raquette retourne à sa position d'origine. Quand Snoopy manque, la balle continue sur, suivie par le son des bouteilles cassées. La marque CRASH apparaît. Snoopy fait semblant de dormir. Charlie Brown lance une raquette dans le désespoir. 2 points lors du retour de la balle de Charlie Brown. 3 points lors du retour de la balle de Lucy. Les scores de bonus sont ceux avec 200 ou 500 points (200, 500, 1200, 1500, ... à 9500). Lorsque chaque score bonus est atteint, fanfare sons et tous les misses sont annulés. Quand un score de bonus est atteint et qu'il n'y a pas de misses enregistrées, le jeu entre dans le "Chance time" pour 50 à 70 secondes. Score clignote sur et en dehors, en revenant la balle de Charlie Brown 5 points, la balle de Lucy marque 6 points. Le score maximal d'affichage est de 9999 points.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Snoopy Tennis-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Snoopy Tennis-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Snoopy Tennis-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19820428T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Turtle Bridge.mgw</path>
		<name>Turtle Bridge</name>
		<desc>Votre personnage tente de convoyer des paquets de la rive gauche à la rive droite d'un lac en traversant sur le dos de tortues. Une fois la traversée effectuée, il retourne sur l'autre berge.
Quand une tortue voit un poisson remonter à la surface, elle plonge dans l'eau. Si votre personnage saute sur une tortue en plongée, c'est raté. La partie se termine après 3 échecs.
En mode de jeu A, la tortue du milieu ne plonge pas (sauf si le personnage reste trop longtemps sur son dos).
3 points sont attribués à chaque fois qu'un paquet est transmis et des points supplémentaires sont accordés au retour sur la berge d'en-face. Plus la traversée est rapide, plus le nombre de points augmente.
Lorsque le joueur atteint un score bonus, tous les échecs sont effacés en fanfare et le jeu continue. Si ce score bonus est atteint sans aucun échec, les tortues ne bougeront plus pendant quelques dizaines de secondes.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Turtle Bridge-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Turtle Bridge-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Turtle Bridge-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19820201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_bfightn.7z</path>
		<name>Balloon Fight (New Wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Balloon Fight is a Crystal Screen and New Wide Screen Game &amp; Watch game released in 1986 (CS) and 1988 (NWS). The game is similar to the NES classic Balloon Fight, particularly its Balloon Trip mode. The model number for the Crystal Screen version is BF-803, while the model number for the New Wide Screen version is BF-107. The BF in the model numbers stands for Balloon Fight.
Like all the Game &amp; Watch units, it has a built-in clock, and it has an alarm as well. To set the alarm, use a pointed object and push the alarm switch. Once you do so, a character by the name of Sparky will come on the screen with a watering can. If he doesn't appear, then you must press the switch again. After this, you can adjust when the alarm will go off. When it does go off, an alarm will sound if you're not playing and Sparky will start to pour water out of his watering can. If you are playing, the alarm won't sound, but Sparky will still pour water out of the can. After the alarm goes off, it will continue to sound for a total of 20 seconds or until you press the time button.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bfightn_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bfightn.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bfightn.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_boxing.7z</path>
		<name>Boxing: Micro Vs. System </name>
		<desc>Boxing is a Micro VS. Game &amp; Watch game released in 1984 by Nintendo. In America, the game was originally known as Punch-Out!! (named after the popular franchise), though when the game was included in Game &amp; Watch Gallery 4 they changed the name back to Boxing. The model number for the game was BX-301. Within the box of the game were the unit, LR44 batteries, and a caution leaflet. In the game, you'll box another character. The game is seen from a 2D perspective, and your character is always on the right.

The only difference between Boxing and Punch-Out!! were the names and the box. The American box had artwork that was made specifically for it.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_boxing_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_boxing.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_boxing.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19840731T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Sport</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_bsweep.7z</path>
		<name>Bombsweeper</name>
		<desc>Bombsweeper was a multi-screen Game &amp; Watch video game released in June of 1987. The game was never released in Japan. The game's model number was BD-62.
	
	Dynamite Jack, a masked bomber, has planted many bombs in the sewers. You play the role of John Solver, who must descend into the sewer and defuse the bombs before it's too late!
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bsweep_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bsweep.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bsweep.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19870601T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_cgrab.7z</path>
		<name>Crab Grab</name>
		<desc>Crab Grab is a Super Color Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1984. It's model number is UD-202. In the game, crabs are moving towards your character. You must push them away and not let them pinch you. If three crabs pinch you, then it'll result in a game over, and you'll have to start over. There are four columns, each a different color (from left to right: purple, green, orange, and blue). The crabs will start to come from the top, and you'll have to move your character from left to right to push them away, though more and more will always come. The game was one of two Super Color games, the other being Spitball Sparky.

When Nintendo of America released the game, they made exclusive art for the box that wasn't present in the Japanese version. They also did this with Spitball Sparky and a couple of other titles. Within the game was a grey leaflet that told the gamer how to play. A similar leaflet was included in Spitball Sparky, though it was yellow instead of grey.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_cgrab_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_cgrab.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_cgrab.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19840221T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_chef.7z</path>
		<name>Chef</name>
		<desc>Chef is a wide-screen Game &amp; Watch game that was released in 1981. An estimated 1,000,000 units were manufactured by Nintendo. The game's model was FP-24, with the FP standing for Frying Pan. The contents within the game's box included the Game &amp; Watch unit, two LR43 batteries, battery stickers, and the game's instructions.

The original Game &amp; Watch game was released as a title in both Game &amp; Watch Gallery 2 and Game &amp; Watch Gallery 4. Enhanced versions were also included that featured Mario characters instead of the traditional ones that were present in the original. Chef also appears as a move Mr. Game &amp; Watch can perform in Super Smash Bros. Melee and Super Smash Bros. Brawl. After the player uses the kitchen timer in Personal Trainer: Cooking, Chef will become an unlockable game.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_chef_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_chef.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_chef.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19810908T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_climber.7z</path>
		<name>Climber (Crystal Screen)</name>
		<desc>Not to be confused with Ice Climber. Climber is a Game &amp; Watch video game released in the Crystal Screen format in 1986 and the New Wide Screen format in 1988. The game was never released in Japan, and an estimated 250,000 of the New Wide Screen version were produced by Nintendo. The model number for the Crystal Screen version is DR-802, while the model number for the New Wide Screen game is DR-106. Some speculate that the game is based on the Ice Climber NES game, though this is unconfirmed.

In Climber, you are a child known as Climber who, with the help of Lord Meiji's teachings, jumps across platforms trying to get to the top of Block Mountain while avoiding enemies and platforms that move. The enemies are the Blockmen, which walk and turn into block platforms when they reach a gap; Eyerom, birds that fly and get in the Climber's way; and thorny plants, which are obstacles in the way of Climber's movements. In each set of 5 levels, the first 4 ends with a bonus game where Climber has 2 chances to time his jump to catch Hentori, the bonus bird. On the fifth level, Climber must jump and grab the sword at the correct time to stab and defeat Dragalo the dragon.

Both versions of the game were essentially the same with only minor differences. There's a cheat in the game where if you press the jump button while also pressing the GAME button, you'll start the game at the sixth level.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_climber_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_climber.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_climber.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_climbern.7z</path>
		<name>Climber (New Wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Not to be confused with Ice Climber. Climber is a Game &amp; Watch video game released in the Crystal Screen format in 1986 and the New Wide Screen format in 1988. The game was never released in Japan, and an estimated 250,000 of the New Wide Screen version were produced by Nintendo. The model number for the Crystal Screen version is DR-802, while the model number for the New Wide Screen game is DR-106. Some speculate that the game is based on the Ice Climber NES game, though this is unconfirmed.

In Climber, you are a child known as Climber who, with the help of Lord Meiji's teachings, jumps across platforms trying to get to the top of Block Mountain while avoiding enemies and platforms that move. The enemies are the Blockmen, which walk and turn into block platforms when they reach a gap; Eyerom, birds that fly and get in the Climber's way; and thorny plants, which are obstacles in the way of Climber's movements. In each set of 5 levels, the first 4 ends with a bonus game where Climber has 2 chances to time his jump to catch Hentori, the bonus bird. On the fifth level, Climber must jump and grab the sword at the correct time to stab and defeat Dragalo the dragon.

Both versions of the game were essentially the same with only minor differences. There's a cheat in the game where if you press the jump button while also pressing the GAME button, you'll start the game at the sixth level.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_climbern_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_climbern.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_climbern.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_dkcirc.7z</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong Circus</name>
		<desc>Donkey Kong Circus is a Panorama Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1984. The game is an extremely rare title. The game is basically the same as Mickey Mouse on the Panorama, though instead of controlling Mickey you control Donkey Kong. In the game, Donkey Kong will juggle sticks, though when a torch comes you're required not to touch it or else you'll be burned.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkcirc_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkcirc.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkcirc.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19840901T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_dkhockey.7z</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong Hockey</name>
		<desc>Donkey Kong Hockey is a Micro VS. Game &amp; Watch game released in 1984 by Nintendo. Of the three Micro VS. Games, it was the last.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkhockey_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkhockey.png</marquee>
		<video />
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19841113T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Sport</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_dkjr.7z</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong Jr. (New Wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Donkey Kong Jr. is a New Wide Screen, Tabletop, and Panorama Game &amp; Watch game initially released in 1982. The Tabletop and Panorama versions are the same game, though the New Wide Screen version is different. The model numbers for the game are DJ-101, CJ-71, and CJ-93 for the New Wide Screen, Tabletop, and Panorama version, respectively. DJ stands for Donkey Kong Jr. while CJ stands for Color Jr. Nintendo manufactured 1,000,000 copies of the New Wide Screen version worldwide, though they only made 250,000 copies each of the other two.

As is the case with all the Game &amp; Watch games, all the three versions of the game feature a clock and an alarm. The clock's alarm can be set when the player pushes the switch button with a sharp object. If done correctly, a bell should appear on the screen in the New Wide Screen version, and in the Tabletop and Panorama version, musical notes will appear. After the time when the alarm is supposed to go off arrives, the alarm will sound (only if you aren't playing the game) and, in the New Wide Screen version Mario will arrive and strike the bell and in the other version, Mario will arrive and whistle the musical notes.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkjr_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkjr.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkjr.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830426T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_dkjrp.7z</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong Jr. (Panorama Screen)</name>
		<desc>Donkey Kong Jr. is a New Wide Screen, Tabletop, and Panorama Game &amp; Watch game initially released in 1982. The Tabletop and Panorama versions are the same game, though the New Wide Screen version is different. The model numbers for the game are DJ-101, CJ-71, and CJ-93 for the New Wide Screen, Tabletop, and Panorama version, respectively. DJ stands for Donkey Kong Jr. while CJ stands for Color Jr. Nintendo manufactured 1,000,000 copies of the New Wide Screen version worldwide, though they only made 250,000 copies each of the other two.

As is the case with all the Game &amp; Watch games, all the three versions of the game feature a clock and an alarm. The clock's alarm can be set when the player pushes the switch button with a sharp object. If done correctly, a bell should appear on the screen in the New Wide Screen version, and in the Tabletop and Panorama version, musical notes will appear. After the time when the alarm is supposed to go off arrives, the alarm will sound (only if you aren't playing the game) and, in the New Wide Screen version Mario will arrive and strike the bell and in the other version, Mario will arrive and whistle the musical notes.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkjrp_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkjrp.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkjrp.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830426T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_dkong.7z</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong</name>
		<desc>Donkey Kong is a Multi Screen Game &amp; Watch game released in 1982. It was based on the arcade game Donkey Kong, with gameplay based only on 25m, the first stage from the arcade version. This was the first Game and Watch game to be based on pre-existing Nintendo characters, and it was the first video game system to include the D-pad, a feature of all future Nintendo systems. The game unit's model is DK-52, with the DK standing for Donkey Kong. The game was a huge success, selling over 1,000,000 copies worldwide. The game comes with 2 LR44 batteries, which should last the player 6 months.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkong_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkong.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkong.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19820603T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_dkong2.7z</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong II</name>
		<desc>Donkey Kong II (ドンキーコングII) est un jeu d'action/plates-formes/puzzle sorti en 1983 sur Game &amp; Watch. C'est d'ailleurs la semi-suite de Donkey Kong Jr. et non la suite de Donkey Kong comme certains pourraient éventuellement le penser et malgré que certaines personnes le disent. Il a été réédité dans le jeu Mario, Game &amp; Watch Gallery 3. Alors que Donkey Kong Jr. sur Game &amp; Watch reprenait le premier niveau de la version arcade du jeu qui est la principale version, Donkey Kong II est plutôt inspiré du troisième et quatrième niveau de la version arcade de Donkey Kong Jr.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkong2_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkong2.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkong2.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830307T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action/Puzzle</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_dkong3.7z</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong III</name>
		<desc>Donkey Kong 3 is a Micro VS. Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1984 by Nintendo. It is one of three multiplayer Game &amp; Watch video games. The model number for Donkey Kong 3 is AK-302, with the AK standing for Attack Kong. The game, while bearing the same title, is entirely different from the arcade game Donkey Kong 3. In this game, one player will control Stanley, and the other will control Donkey Kong. Nintendo manufactured 250,000 units of the game worldwide.

As is the case with all Game &amp; Watch games, Donkey Kong 3 features a clock and an alarm. The alarm can be set when the player pushes a sharp object in the alarm switch. If done correctly, an image of a bell will appear on the screen. Once the time arrives, the bell will start moving, and the alarm will sound, the latter of which only occurring if the player isn't playing the game.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkong3_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkong3.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkong3.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19840820T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_egg.7z</path>
		<name>Egg</name>
		<desc>Egg is a Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1981. The game was similar to the previously released Mickey Mouse game, though due to copyright issues which prevented them from using the brand in some countries, they replaced Mickey Mouse with a wolf, though the gameplay remains essentially the same. The countries where Mickey Mouse was replaced by Egg include some Asian countries and Australia. In the Soviet Union there were the wolf and the hare from Soviet animated TV series Nu, Pogodi!. Egg was never released in Japan. Within the box were LR43 batteries, a caution leaflet, and battery stickers. The game sold an estimated 250,000 units worldwide. The game's model number is EG-26.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_egg_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_egg.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_egg.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19811009T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_fire.7z</path>
		<name>Fire (Wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Fire is a game where you control two firemen trying to bounce people falling from a burning building to an ambulance. This game was originally released in the Silver series on July 31, 1980. On December 4, 1981, the game was re-released as a part of the Wide Screen series.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_fire_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_fire.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_fire.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19811202T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_fires.7z</path>
		<name>Fire (Silver)</name>
		<desc>Fire is a game where you control two firemen trying to bounce people falling from a burning building to an ambulance. This game was originally released in the Silver series on July 31, 1980. On December 4, 1981, the game was re-released as a part of the Wide Screen series.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_fires_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_fires.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_fires.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19800731T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_fireatk.7z</path>
		<name>Fire Attack</name>
		<desc>The Game &amp; Watch game Fire Attack, released March 26, 1982, was a game where your character is a civil war-looking general, trying to defend his fort from an onslaught of Native Americans attacking with flaming torches.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_fireatk_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_fireatk.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_fireatk.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19820326T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_flagman.7z</path>
		<name>Flagman</name>
		<desc>Flagman is a game in the Game and Watch Silver Series released on May 6, 1980. It features a character holding up flags.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_flagman_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_flagman.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_flagman.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19800506T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_gcliff.7z</path>
		<name>Gold Cliff</name>
		<desc>Gold Cliff is a multi-screen Game &amp; Watch game about collecting treasure. The player controls an archaeologist and scales disappearing platforms in the ancient ruins. In every set of 4 levels, the first 3 require the player to grab a key on the right side of the ruins and take the key to the top left to progress. In the 4th level, the player must grab a sword on the left side of the ruins and take it to the top. At the top of the ruins, an enemy will be moving; to defeat it, the player must press up on the D-pad to stab the enemy when it is directly above. Each level is timed, and when the timer hits 30, crabs begin to appear, and will result in a miss if the touch the player.

Gold Cliff was released in 1988, making it the last Game &amp; Watch to be released before the Game Boy. This was the first Game and Watch to include a Continue button, which starts the player at the level they left off on the last time they played.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_gcliff_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_gcliff.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_gcliff.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19861001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_ghouse.7z</path>
		<name>Green House</name>
		<desc>Greenhouse is also referenced in the Super Smash Bros. series, as Mr. Game &amp; Watch's neutral attack, or jab. Green House is an attack used by Mr. Game &amp; Watch in which he uses a small pump and attacks with small puffs of gas which can be used repeatedly.

A microgame in the Nintendo DS video game WarioWare D.I.Y. is titled Greenhouse and is based on the Game &amp; Watch game.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_ghouse_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_ghouse.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_ghouse.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19821216T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_helmet.7z</path>
		<name>Helmet (CN-17 version)</name>
		<desc>Helmet is a game in the Gold series where you have to dodge tools and get to the door on the right. It was released on Febuary 21, 1981.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_helmet_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_helmet.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_helmet.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19810221T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_judge.7z</path>
		<name>Judge (green version)</name>
		<desc>Judge is a game in the Silver series released on October 4, 1980. Two versions of this game were released- a Green version, and a Purple version.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_judge_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_judge.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_judge.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19841004T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_lboat.7z</path>
		<name>Lifeboat</name>
		<desc>Lifeboat is a multi-screen Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1983. Nintendo produced an estimated 500,000 units worldwide. The model number for the game was TC-58. In the game, you'll have to maneuver two lifeboats and catch people who are jumping out of a ship on fire. The game was held similarly to how you would hold a book. Lifeboat was mentioned in the German magazine Telematch in 1984.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_lboat_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_lboat.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_lboat.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19831025T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_lion.7z</path>
		<name>Lion</name>
		<desc>The goal of the game is to keep the lions from escaping from their cages. Both zookeepers are controlled separately using the corresponding buttons. The lions will try to escape. To prevent them from doing so, position a zookeeper in front of the lion. The lions can also try to "fake-out" the player. Each time you prevent a lion from escaping, you score one point. The maximum score is 999. If a lion escapes, an animation will play of the zookeeper hiding in a tree, and you will get one miss. The game ends when you get three misses.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_lion_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_lion.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_lion.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19810101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_manhole.7z</path>
		<name>Manhole (New Wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Manhole is a game where you have to prevent pedestrians from falling into the water. It was first released on January 29, 1981, as a part of the Gold Series. It was later re-released as a part of the New Wide Screen series on August 24, 1983.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_manhole_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_manhole.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_manhole.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830824T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_manholeg.7z</path>
		<name>Manhole (Gold)</name>
		<desc>Manhole is a game where you have to prevent pedestrians from falling into the water. It was first released on January 29, 1981, as a part of the Gold Series. It was later re-released as a part of the New Wide Screen series on August 24, 1983.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_manholeg_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_manholeg.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_manholeg.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19810129T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_mario.7z</path>
		<name>Mario Bros.</name>
		<desc>Mario Bros. is a multi-screen Game &amp; Watch video game that stars Mario and Luigi. It marks the debut of Luigi. The Multi Screen unit is held sideways in a similar fashion to reading a book. The game was released in 1983 by Nintendo, and while it has the same name as Mario Bros. in the arcades, the game is not based on it, actually coming before the arcade version. Nintendo manufactured 1,000,000 units of the game worldwide. The game's model number is MW-56. The M stands for Mario, though it's unclear what the W stands for. Within the game's box were the game unit, two LR44 batteries, and instruction booklet and battery stickers.

As in all Game &amp; Watch games, Mario Bros. contains a clock that has an alarm. The alarm can be set by using a sharp object and pressing the alarm switch. If done correctly, an image of a bell should appear. Following this, you can set when the alarm should go off. Once the time arrives, an alarm will sound and the bell will start to move. If the player is playing the game, then the alarm will not sound, but the bell will still move. The alarm will continue to ring for about one minute.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mario_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mario.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mario.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830314T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_mariocm.7z</path>
		<name>Mario's Cement Factory (New Wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Mario's Cement Factory is a Game &amp; Watch video game released in both the Tabletop and New Wide Screen formats in 1983. The game starred, as the name suggests, Mario. For the New Wide Screen version, Nintendo produced an estimated 750,000 copies of the game. The amount that they made for the Tabletop version is unknown. The model number for the New Wide Screen version was ML-102, while the Tabletop's was CM-72. The model number for the Tabletop version of Mario's Cement Factory has caused some confusion, though it was revealed later than in a German magazine, an image of the game was shown and the logo read "Concrete Mixer", suggesting that the game was initially going to be called that, and explaining the model number. Within the New Wide Screen's version box was the actual game, LR44 batteries, a caution leaflet, and battery stickers.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariocm_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariocm.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariocm.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830616T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_mariocmt.7z</path>
		<name>Mario's Cement Factory (Table Top)</name>
		<desc>Mario's Cement Factory is a Game &amp; Watch video game released in both the Tabletop and New Wide Screen formats in 1983. The game starred, as the name suggests, Mario. For the New Wide Screen version, Nintendo produced an estimated 750,000 copies of the game. The amount that they made for the Tabletop version is unknown. The model number for the New Wide Screen version was ML-102, while the Tabletop's was CM-72. The model number for the Tabletop version of Mario's Cement Factory has caused some confusion, though it was revealed later than in a German magazine, an image of the game was shown and the logo read "Concrete Mixer", suggesting that the game was initially going to be called that, and explaining the model number. Within the New Wide Screen's version box was the actual game, LR44 batteries, a caution leaflet, and battery stickers.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariocmt_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariocmt.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariocmt.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830428T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_mariotj.7z</path>
		<name>Mario The Juggler</name>
		<desc>Mario the Juggler was the final Game &amp; Watch released on October 14, 1991. This is like a make of Ball but Mario juggling items. If he misses he gets made fun of by a Toad.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariotj_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariotj.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariotj.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19911014T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_mariotj.7z</path>
		<name>Mario The Juggler</name>
		<desc>Mario the Juggler was the final Game &amp; Watch released on October 14, 1991. This is like a make of Ball but Mario juggling items. If he misses he gets made fun of by a Toad.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariotj_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariotj.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariotj.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19911014T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_mbaway.7z</path>
		<name>Mario's Bombs Away</name>
		<desc>Mario's Bombs Away is a game released as a Game &amp; Watch. The game consisted of moving a military-clad Mario from left to right and strategically placing bombs. As part of the Panorama screen series, the game was in color, and is played by watching a mirror in which the screen was reflected rather than by looking directly at the screen.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mbaway_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mbaway.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mbaway.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19831110T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_mickdon.7z</path>
		<name>Mickey &amp; Donald</name>
		<desc>Mickey &amp; Donald is a Multi Screen Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1982 by Nintendo. It stars the two Disney properties Mickey Mouse and Donald Duck. The game's model number is DM-53 (D standing for Donald and M standing for Mickey). The second release of the game didn't include the leaflet explaining to the player how to control the game. In the game, you'll control both of the characters whose goals are to extinguish fires.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mickdon_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mickdon.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mickdon.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19821112T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_mmouse.7z</path>
		<name>Mickey Mouse (Wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Mickey Mouse is two different Game &amp; Watch video games that first was released as a Wide Screen game in 1981. In 1984 there was a Panorama game released with the same name, but with completely different gameplay. The Wide screen issue was one of the better selling Game &amp; Watch video games with an astonishing 1,200,000 copies sold, and understandably so as it stars the popular Mickey Mouse character. It was developed by Nintendo and was released on October 9, 1981. The panorama issue is much rarer and highly sought after from collectors.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mmouse_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mmouse.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mmouse.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19811009T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_mmousep.7z</path>
		<name>Mickey Mouse (Panorama Screen)</name>
		<desc>Mickey Mouse is two different Game &amp; Watch video games that first was released as a Wide Screen game in 1981. In 1984 there was a Panorama game released with the same name, but with completely different gameplay. The Wide screen issue was one of the better selling Game &amp; Watch video games with an astonishing 1,200,000 copies sold, and understandably so as it stars the popular Mickey Mouse character. It was developed by Nintendo and was released on October 9, 1981. The panorama issue is much rarer and highly sought after from collectors.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mmousep_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mmousep.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mmousep.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19840101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_octopus.7z</path>
		<name>Octopus</name>
		<desc>Octopus is a game in the Wide Screen series released on July 16, 1981. It features divers trying to get treasure.
	
	There are two buttons- one for moving the diver left/up, and one for moving right/down. The goal of the game is to collect treasure and return it to the boat. The Octopus' tentacles will try to grab the divers. If it grabs one, you lose one diver. The game ends when all three divers are grabbed by the Octopus.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_octopus_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_octopus.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_octopus.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19810716T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_opanic.7z</path>
		<name>Oil Panic</name>
		<desc>Oil Panic is a video game unit that was released as part of the Game &amp; Watch multi screen series. In the game, the player has to catch dripping oil from an oil leak in a pipe. Once he does, he has to go into his bosses room on the second screen to empty it. If he misses a drop then the player loses a life.
	
	Two customers are waiting at a gas station to fuel up. Meanwhile, an oil leak from a pipe on the third floor is causing confusion. Move Station Helper left and right by pressing the control buttons to catch the leaks in his bucket. Oil falls in drops. Helper's bucket holds three drops. Move Helper out to veranda to pour the oil in his bucket into the Boss's oil drum on the second floor. Be Careful not to drop oil on the waiting customers.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_opanic_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_opanic.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_opanic.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19820528T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_pchute.7z</path>
		<name>Parachute</name>
		<desc>Parachute is a game in the Wide Screen Series released on June 19, 1981. It features a man in a boat rescuing parachuting men.
	
	The goal of the game is to save the men parachuting from the helicopter. To do so, position the boat below the place where the men are parachuting towards. In Game B, sometimes men will get stuck on the palm tree to the right. For every man you save, you get one point. The maximum score is 999 points. If a man parachutes into the water, an animation plays of them getting chased by a shark, and you get one miss. The game ends when you get three misses.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_pchute_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_pchute.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_pchute.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19810619T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_popeye.7z</path>
		<name>Popeye (Wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Popeye is a Wide Screen Game &amp; Watch game released in 1981, under license from King Features Syndicate. The model code for this game is PP-23.

Gameplay: Players take control of Popeye The Sailor Man as he catches the things thrown by Olive Oyl. Missing 1 item is not a miss, but the 2nd time an item falls into the water, or Popeye is hit by Bluto's attacks counts as a miss. The game ends when the player gets 3 misses. In Game A, Bluto will try to hit Popeye with a hammer on the left, but in Game B, not only will Bluto try to hit Popeye with a hammer on the left, he will also try to punch him on the right, and will still count as a miss if Popeye gets punched. Olive Oyl swings a bell when the alarm goes off.

Trivia: Popeye was also released for the Tabletop and Panorama Game &amp; Watch games, but those are different then the Wide Screen version. The alarm tone is also used in Helmet, Octopus, Parachute, and the Wide Screen re-release of Fire.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_popeye_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_popeye.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_popeye.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19810101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_popeyep.7z</path>
		<name>Popeye (Panorama Screen)</name>
		<desc>Unlike its predecessor, the newer game employs color graphics over a black background. An entirely different game, it focuses on Popeye fighting Brutus to rescue the kidnapped Olive. Both opponents stand face-to-face on a pier and throw punches at each other, with the hero controlled by moving left and right and using a punch button. Popeye has to force his enemy towards the left by attacking him until he falls into the water, doing this three times in a row will make spinach available and result in Olive's rescue. If Popeye were to fall from the right edge, he would lose a life. Losing all three results in a game over. Also, in the harder setting, a swordfish will appear that may stab Popeye trough the pier and push him closer to the edge.

This game was released in two versions: a handheld "Panorama Screen" unit, and a "Table Top" version that stood upright and resembled a miniature arcade cabinet, complete with a small joystick used for the side-to-side movement.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_popeyep_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_popeyep.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_popeyep.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_rshower.7z</path>
		<name>Rain Shower</name>
		<desc>Rain Shower is a multiscreen Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1983. It was released in 1983 and Nintendo reportedly made an estimated 250,000 units worldwide. In the game, your clothes are hanging up to dry outside, but it's about to rain, and you have to make sure your clothes don't get wet. The rain comes down in segments, so you can move the wire from left to right to make sure the segment of rain that's coming down don't get onto your clothes.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_rshower_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_rshower.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_rshower.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_sbuster.7z</path>
		<name>Safe Buster</name>
		<desc>Safebuster is a multi-screen Game &amp; Watch game released in January of 1988. The game was never released in Japan. The game's model number was JB-63. Worldwide Nintendo manufactured an estimated 500,000 Safebuster models. A pocket size version of Safebuster was also released in America and Europe. 
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_sbuster_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_sbuster.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_sbuster.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19880112T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_smbn.7z</path>
		<name>Super Mario Bros. (New Wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Super Mario Bros. for the Game &amp; Watch was a game that was released on the Crystal Screen and New Wide Screen unit. While the exact date of its release is unknown, it can be confirmed that it was released sometime in June of 1986 and March of 1988. A special edition of the game, which came with a winner certificate, a license card, and battery cover stickers, and a copy of the game in a Diskun-shaped case was given away in August of 1987.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_smbn_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_smbn.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_smbn.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19880308T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_snoopyp.7z</path>
		<name>Snoopy (Panorama Screen)</name>
		<desc>Snoopy for the Game &amp; Watch was a game that was released on the Panorama Screen unit in 1983.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_snoopyp_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_snoopyp.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_snoopyp.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_squish.7z</path>
		<name>Squish</name>
		<desc>Squish is a Multi Screen Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1986 by Nintendo. The game was never released in Japan. A Pocketsize version of the game was also released. The unit's model number was MG-61. In the game, you have to avoid the platforms that are coming towards the player character, Ziggy the Mazeman. The game's name comes from the fact that you'll be "squished" if a platform hits you. The top screen contained game information, while all of the action took place on the bottom screen. This and Zelda were the only two games to have a format like this when it came to multi-screen games.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_squish_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_squish.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_squish.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19860401T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_ssparky.7z</path>
		<name>Spitball Sparky</name>
		<desc>Spitball Sparky is a Super Color Game &amp; Watch game released in 1984 by Nintendo. The game's model number was BU-201, and the contents within the box included the game, LR44 batteries, a caution leaflet, a how to play leaflet, and battery stickers. The game is very similar to the arcade classic Arcanoid and has colors due to the layers of colored plastic overlay. Your goal is to spit on the ball so that it'll go back up and destroy the blocks at the top. The unit was rectangular and silver. When Nintendo of America released the game in America, they made artwork for the game that had a more detailed character.

Interestingly when Nintendo was manufacturing the game, a few of the units came out white instead of the regular silver color. Nintendo didn't notice the mistake and released the game. Today the white version of Spitball Sparky is extremely rare and is a collector's item. In the May of 1984 issue of German magazine Telematch, there was information contained within regarding Spitball Sparky, one of the few if not only appearance of the game in print.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_ssparky_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_ssparky.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_ssparky.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19840207T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_tbridge.7z</path>
		<name>Turtle Bridge</name>
		<desc>Turtle Bridge is a widescreen Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1982 by Nintendo. In the game, you must get the character from one side of a lake to the other by jumping on the shells of turtles that are protruding from the water. If you jump on a turtle at the wrong time, then you will have to go back to the beginning. The fact that the turtles gain your character access to the other side of the lake is where the game's name originates from.

Contents within the game box include the Game &amp; Watch unit, LR43 batteries, a caution leaflet, battery stickers, and, in the first edition of the game, an error leaflet which cautioned players of an error in the game's instruction booklet which was later corrected in future versions. The model number for the game was TL-28. The game sold an estimated 500,000 units worldwide. It is currently unknown if a pocket-sized version was ever released. There is an estimated 200 to 500 Bosch versions of the game, which were only released through promotions.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_tbridge_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_tbridge.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_tbridge.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19820201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_tfish.7z</path>
		<name>Tropical Fish</name>
		<desc>Tropical Fish is a rare New Wide Screen Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1985. The game was never released in Japan. The model number for Tropical Fish is TF-104. In the game, you'll merge fish from an aquarium into another aquarium via a fishbowl. Overall, the gameplay is very similar to Fire, though perhaps slightly improved. Tropical Fish has also appeared as an unlockable museum game in Game &amp; Watch Gallery 4, albeit in Classic only.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_tfish_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_tfish.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_tfish.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19850701T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_vermin.7z</path>
		<name>Vermin</name>
		<desc>Vermin is a game in the Game and Watch Silver Series released on July 10, 1980. In the game, you play as a character with two hammers trying to get rid of moles.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_vermin_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_vermin.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_vermin.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19800710T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_zelda.7z</path>
		<name>Zelda</name>
		<desc>Game &amp; Watch: Zelda (serial number ZL-65) is a handheld LCD game developed by Gunpei Yokoi and Nintendo R&amp;D1 and released in August 1989 in North America, as part of Nintendo's Game &amp; Watch Multi Screen series. It is the first handheld Zelda title, coming out four years before The Legend of Zelda: Link's Awakening. Similar to other Multi Screen games, it has two screens with a hinge in the center and the buttons on the bottom half, making it look strikingly similar to the Nintendo DS. It is a side-scrolling action game, and the gameplay and items are inspired by Zelda II: The Adventure of Link.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_zelda_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_zelda.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_zelda.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19890826T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./bassmate.7z</path>
		<name>Bassmate Computer</name>
		<desc>The Bassmate I saw was sold under the name of a brand called "Probe 2000" and dated from 1984. At first glance, it seemed like a regular sporting aid, be it one that was quite advanced for its time.

However, when checking out the image on the back of the box, something dawned on me. That shape seemed rather familiar! It looked just like a Game &amp; Watch Multi Screen!

When taking a closer look, it appeared that everything matched; the overall design of the case, the hinges, the connector between the bottom and top part, the shape of the buttons - they all looked like they came straight out of the kitchen of the handheld master from Kyoto.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/bassmate_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/bassmate.png</marquee>
		<video />
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19840101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gnw_pinball.7z</path>
		<name>Pinball</name>
		<desc>Pinball is a Multi Screen Game &amp; Watch game released in December of 1983. Nintendo manufactured around 250,000 units of the game worldwide. It's basically just a portable pinball game where you control two flippers. The goal is to keep the ball above the flippers by hitting it. The ball will then go in a fairly random direction and hit the bumpers, thus giving the player points. The model number for the game was PB-59, with PB standing for Pinball. The game's box came with the unit, two LR44 batteries, an instruction booklet and battery stickers.

As is the case with all Game &amp; Watch games, Pinball has a clock with an alarm. If you wish to set the alarm, then you should use a sharp object and push the switch. If done correctly, a bell will appear. The bell is the game's alarm icon. Following this, you can set the time for when the alarm will sound. Once the time arrives, the bell will start to move and flash while the alarm will sound. If you're playing the game, the bell will still move around, though the alarm will not sound.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_pinball_system.png</image>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_pinball.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_pinball.png</marquee>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19831105T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20201106T024604</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gnw_stennis.7z</path>
		<name>Snoopy Tennis</name>
		<desc>Snoopy Tennis is a Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1982 by Nintendo. The game was very successful, perhaps due to the Snoopy label, with Nintendo producing an estimated 1,200,000 worldwide. In the game, you control Snoopy, moving him up and down to make him hit the oncoming tennis balls with your racket. It was released on the Wide Screen format. A version of the game was released as a keychain title under the mini-classics label. The control button leaflet, which was only present in this game's box and Fire Attack's, showcases various characters from the Peanuts franchise. Unsurprisingly, due to licensing issues, the game was not released in any of the Game &amp; Watch video games, though it was mentioned in Super Smash Bros. Brawl for the Wii.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_stennis_system.png</image>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_stennis.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_stennis.png</marquee>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19820428T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20201106T024644</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gnw_smb.7z</path>
		<name>Super Mario Bros. (Crystal Screen)</name>
		<desc>Super Mario Bros. for the Game &amp; Watch was a game that was released on the Crystal Screen and New Wide Screen unit. While the exact date of its release is unknown, it can be confirmed that it was released sometime in June of 1986 and March of 1988. A special edition of the game, which came with a winner certificate, a license card, and battery cover stickers, and a copy of the game in a Diskun-shaped case was given away in August of 1987.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_smb_system.png</image>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_smb.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_smb.png</marquee>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19860625T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20201106T024717</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gnw_ball.7z</path>
		<name>Ball</name>
		<desc>Ball est le premier jeu de la gamme de jeux électroniques Game and Watch créée par Nintendo. Il appartient à la série Silver. Le joueur contrôle les bras d'un personnage (Mr. Game and Watch) dans le but de rattraper des balles qui tombent et donc de jongler. Il y a deux modes de jeu : "game A", dans lequel le joueur jongle avec deux balles et "game B" où il jongle avec trois balles. Il n'y a que deux boutons d'action : gauche et droite. Comme sur n'importe quel Game and Watch, il est possible de lire l'heure.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_ball_system.png</image>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_ball.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_ball.png</marquee>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19800428T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20201106T134503</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gnw_bfight.7z</path>
		<name>Balloon Fight (Crystal Screen)</name>
		<desc>Balloon Fight is a Crystal Screen and New Wide Screen Game &amp; Watch game released in 1986 (CS) and 1988 (NWS). The game is similar to the NES classic Balloon Fight, particularly its Balloon Trip mode. The model number for the Crystal Screen version is BF-803, while the model number for the New Wide Screen version is BF-107. The BF in the model numbers stands for Balloon Fight.
Like all the Game &amp; Watch units, it has a built-in clock, and it has an alarm as well. To set the alarm, use a pointed object and push the alarm switch. Once you do so, a character by the name of Sparky will come on the screen with a watering can. If he doesn't appear, then you must press the switch again. After this, you can adjust when the alarm will go off. When it does go off, an alarm will sound if you're not playing and Sparky will start to pour water out of his watering can. If you are playing, the alarm won't sound, but Sparky will still pour water out of the can. After the alarm goes off, it will continue to sound for a total of 20 seconds or until you press the time button.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bfight_system.png</image>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bfight.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bfight.png</marquee>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20201107T031150</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gnw_bjack.7z</path>
		<name>Black Jack</name>
		<desc>Black Jack is a Multi Screen Game &amp; Watch game released in 1985 by Nintendo. A Pocketsize version was also released. The model number for the game was BJ-60 (BJ obviously standing for Black Jack). The contents within the box include the Game &amp; Watch unit, LR44 batteries, a caution leaflet, a ball/score leaflet, and battery stickers. For some reason, there are some Black Jack games that were included in white boxes that Nintendo sent out to retailers. The reason for the white box is unknown, though it's also been confirmed that Donkey Kong 2 and Super Mario Bros. featured similar boxes.

The game is simply Black Jack on an LCD screen. The game is very different from the standard Game &amp; Watch games. If your cards amount to a combined number of 21, then you win the game. Black Jack is the last Game &amp; Watch video games to be released in Japan. All games released after Black Jack were released only in other countries, despite being made in Japan.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bjack_system.png</image>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bjack.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bjack.png</marquee>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19850101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Casino</genre>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20201107T214902</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game id="88055" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Donkey Kong (Multi Screen).mgw</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong (multi Screen)</name>
		<desc>Mario doit atteindre le sommet de la structure et activer un levier qui va mettre une grue à sa portée.
Ensuite, il doit sauter de la grue et démolir peu à peu la structure sur laquelle Donkey Kong se trouve afin de sauver Pauline.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong (Multi Screen)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong (Multi Screen)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong (Multi Screen)-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19820603T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="99461" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Donkey Kong Circus (Panorama).mgw</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong Circus</name>
		<desc>Donkey Kong jongle avec des ananas tout en étant en équilibrant sur un baril.
Attrapez les ananas, mais méfiez-vous des boules de feu.
Des vies sont perdues, si un ananas tombe sur le sol ou si Donkey Kong touche une boule de feu.
Quand toutes les vies sont utilisées le jeu se termine.
Vous gagnez 1 point pour chaque ananas rattrapé.
Le plus gros score affichable est 999.
Au bout de 300 points tous les accidents sont annulés.
Si il n'y a pas eut de vie de perdue au bout de 300 points, le jeu passe en "Chance-Time": tous les points sont attribués au double de la valeur (2 points par ananas rattrapé) jusqu'à ce que vous perdiez une vie.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong Circus (Panorama)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong Circus (Panorama)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong Circus (Panorama)-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19840906T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre />
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88056" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Donkey Kong II (Multi Screen).mgw</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong 2</name>
		<desc>La suite de la célèbre histoire de Donkey Kong.
Mario à enchaîné Donkey Kong, vous devez le délivrer.
Déplacez Donkey Kong junior jusqu'à l'endroit où son papa est retenu prisonnier.
Sur le chemin récupéré la clé d'un des cadenas et faite attention aux alligators, étincelles, oiseaux.

Lorsque Donkey Kong junior atteint l'écran supérieur avec la clé, il doit choisir quel cadenas ouvrir.
Une fois prés du verrou en haut de la chaine appuyez sur la touche "plus" pour l'ouvrir</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong II (Multi Screen)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong II (Multi Screen)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong II (Multi Screen)-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830307T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88098" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Donkey Kong Jr (Panorama).mgw</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong Jr. (panorama Screen)</name>
		<desc>Donkey Kong a été capturé par Mario.
Donkey Kong Jr. doit le libérer de ses chaînes.
Sur le chemin Donkey Kong Jr. est  attaqué par des oiseaux.
Il utilise des parapluies et des ballons pour sauter depuis les hauteurs, et  atteindre les cadenas.
Quand il ouvre les 4 cadenas, Donkey Kong est libre.
Chaque fois qu'il ouvre une serrure, Donkey Kong Jr. doit recommencer du début pour récupérer la clé, puis repart libérer son père.
Au bout de trois essaies, le jeu se termine.
Le plus gros score affichable est de 999 points.
Au bout de 999 points marqué le jeux reprend de zéro à une vitesse plus élevée.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong Jr (Panorama)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Donkey Kong Jr (Panorama)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkjrp.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>01010101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="99462" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Egg.mgw</path>
		<name>Egg</name>
		<desc>Les poulets pondent des oeufs.
Contrôlez le loup afin qu'il les attrape dans son chapeau.
Quand le loup laisse tomber un oeuf, vous ne marquez pas de point.
Le coq apparaît/disparaît toutes les cinq secondes.
Lorsque le coq apparaît alors que l'oeuf tombe, vous perdez un essai.
Au bout de trois essai, le jeu se termine.
Vous gagnez 1 point par oeuf dans le chapeau.
A 200 et 500 points, une musique retentit et vous regagnez les essais perdus.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Egg-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Egg-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Egg-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19811009T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre />
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88072" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Lifeboat (Multi Screen).mgw</path>
		<name>Lifeboat</name>
		<desc>Un incendie éclate sur un bateau de luxe; Les passagers sautent du navire. Il faut mettre l'embarcation de sauvetage en position pour attraper les passagers. Chaque embarcation de sauvetage peut accueillir jusqu'à quatre passagers. Il ya un rivage à gauche et à droite de l'écran. Lorsqu'un canot de sauvetage atteint la rive, les passagers se déchargent automatiquement. 1 point par personne. 1 point par personne déchargé au rivage. Le score maximum affiché est de 999. A 300 points, les sons de fanfare et tous les misses sont annulés; S'il n'y a pas de points manqués lorsque 300 points sont atteints, le jeu se déroule dans «Chance-Time»: le score clignote et tous les points sont attribués à la double valeur (2 points par passager pris ou déchargé au rivage)</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Lifeboat (Multi Screen)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Lifeboat (Multi Screen)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Lifeboat (Multi Screen)-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19831016T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88073" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Mario Bros (Multi Screen).mgw</path>
		<name>Mario Bros.</name>
		<desc>Mario est de retour en action avec son frère Luigi, travaillant dans une usine d'embouteillage, le chargement des caisses sur un tapis roulant. Le convoyeur transporte les caisses pour le chargement sur les camions. Exploite Mario et Luigi en haut et en bas des échelles afin d'obtenir des caisses. Quand une caisses est abandonné, le contremaître se met en colère et un misse est marqué. Trois misses et le jeu est terminé .  1 point par carton chargé sur un convoyeur. 10 points par camion chargé de 8 caisses. À 300 points fanfare sonne et tous les misses sont annulés; S'il n'y a pas de manquer quand 300 points sont atteints, le jeu entre dans "CHANCE TIME". Score clignote et tous les points sont attribués à la double valeur jusqu'à ce que l'erreur soit faite. Le score maximum affiché est de 999 points.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Mario Bros (Multi Screen)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Mario Bros (Multi Screen)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Mario Bros (Multi Screen)-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>01010101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88074" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Mario's Bombs Away (Panorama).mgw</path>
		<name>Mario's Bombs Away</name>
		<desc>Mario est dans la jungle et se bat contre une armée ennemie.nnLe but est de déposer cinq bombes sur le côté droit de la jungle. Lorsque les cinq bombes sont en place, elles explosent et l'armée ennemie est vaincue.nnLes ennemis essaient d'allumer la bombe. Soulevez / baissez la bombe pour la garder en sécurité.nnSi les torches de l'ennemi atteignent la bombe, tous les progrès (les bombes déjà placées) sont perdus.nnTrois échecs et le jeu se termine.nnVous obtenez 1 point quand Mario fait un pas en avant, 5 points quand Mario livre une bombe, 10 points lorsque Mario livre la cinquième bombe.nnUne fanfare retentit à 300 points et toutes les erreurs sont annulées - s'il n'y a pas eu d'erreur alors le jeu entre en "Chance-Time", le marqueur clignote et tous les points attribués ont une valeur double jusqu'à ce qu'une faute soit commise.nnLe score maximum affiché est de 999 points.nnÀ 999 points, le score est réinitialisé et la partie reprend (à une vitesse supérieure).</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Mario's Bombs Away (Panorama)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Mario's Bombs Away (Panorama)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Mario's Bombs Away (Panorama)-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>01010101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88075" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Mickey Mouse (Panorama).mgw</path>
		<name>Mickey Mouse (panorama Screen)</name>
		<desc>Mickey Mouse effectue des acrobaties avec des baguettes tout en se balançant sur une balle dans un cirque. Donald Duck surveille les exploits. Déplacez Mickey à gauche et à droite pour attraper les baguettes, mais méfiez-vous des torches enflammées. Une erreur est enregistrée lorsque Mickey ne parvient pas à attraper une baguette ou lorsqu'il attrape une torche enflammée. Trois erreurs et le jeu se termine. 1 point est donné pour chaque baguette attrapée. Le score maximum affiché est de 999. À 300 points, la fanfare retentit et toutes les erreurs sont annulées. S'il n'y a pas eu d'erreur, le jeu passe en "Chance-Time", tous les points attribués ont une valeur double jusqu'à la première erreur.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Mickey Mouse (Panorama)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Mickey Mouse (Panorama)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mmousep.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>01010101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88076" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Mickey Mouse (Wide Screen).mgw</path>
		<name>Mickey Mouse (wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Les poules pondent des oeufs. Contrôle Mickey Mouse de sorte qu'il les attrape dans son panier. Quand Mickey Mouse laisse tomber un oeuf, un miss est marqué. Minnie apparaît / disparaît toutes les cinq secondes. Lorsque Minnie apparaît alors que l'oeuf tombe, la moitié de miss est marquée (la marque manquante clignote). Trois miss complets et le jeu est terminé. 1 point par oeuf pris. À 200 et 500 points, s'il y a un ou plusieurs ratés, les sons de fanfare et tous les miss sont annulés. Le score maximum affiché est de 999 points.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Mickey Mouse (Wide Screen)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Mickey Mouse (Wide Screen)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Mickey Mouse (Wide Screen)-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19811009T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88082" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Parachute.mgw</path>
		<name>Parachute</name>
		<desc>Un hélicoptère largue des parachutistes. Le joueur, qui contrôle un rameur dans une barque grâce aux 2 boutons (gauche et droite), doit rattraper le parachutiste avant qu'il ne tombe à l'eau et se fasse dévorer par les requins.
Chaque parachutiste récupéré vaut 1 point mais chaque parachutiste qui va à la mer donne un malus matérialisé par une tête de requin. Au bout de 3 malus, la partie est terminée. Si le joueur atteint 200 points puis 500 points, les malus sont supprimés et une petite musique retenti.
Il existe 2 type de jeu (type A et type B). La seule différence du jeu en type B est que les parachutistes peuvent ou non rester accrochés à un palmier et se décrochent de façon aléatoire ce qui augmente la difficulté du jeu.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Parachute-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Parachute-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Parachute-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19810619T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88088" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Snoopy (Panorama).mgw</path>
		<name>Snoopy (panorama Screen)</name>
		<desc>Shroeder joue de son piano. Les notes volent dans l'air jusqu'à l'endroit où Woodstock dort. Orienter Snoopy à gauche et à droite pour frapper les notes avec son marteau afin que Woodstock puisse dormir en paix. Si une note arrive jusqu'à lui, une erreur se produit. Trois erreurs et la partie est terminée. Jeu A: 3 lignes de notes. Jeu B: 4 lignes de notes. 1 point pour chaque note abattue. A 300 points, une musique est jouée et toutes les erreurs sont annulées. S'il n'y a pas eu d'erreur quand les 300 points sont atteints, le jeu passe en "Chance-Time", le score clignote et tous les points ont une valeur double jusqu'à ce qu'une erreur soit commise. Le score affichable maximum est de 999 points. À 999 points, le score est réinitialisé et le jeu recommence (à une vitesse supérieure).</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Snoopy (Panorama)-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Snoopy (Panorama)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Snoopy (Panorama)-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>01010101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88090" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Snoopy Tennis.mgw</path>
		<name>Snoopy Tennis</name>
		<desc>Charlie Brown et Snoopy jouent au tennis. Snoopy doit grimper à l'arbre pour recevoir le service de Charlie Brown. Lucy ne cesse d intercepte la balle de snoopy et de la renvoie . Presser lorsque la balle est juste en face du visage Snoopy. Lorsque Snoopy bascule et manque, il ne peut pas bouger jusqu'à ce que sa raquette retourne à sa position d'origine. Quand Snoopy manque, la balle continue sur, suivie par le son des bouteilles cassées. La marque CRASH apparaît. Snoopy fait semblant de dormir. Charlie Brown lance une raquette dans le désespoir. 2 points lors du retour de la balle de Charlie Brown. 3 points lors du retour de la balle de Lucy. Les scores de bonus sont ceux avec 200 ou 500 points (200, 500, 1200, 1500, ... à 9500). Lorsque chaque score bonus est atteint, fanfare sons et tous les misses sont annulés. Quand un score de bonus est atteint et qu'il n'y a pas de misses enregistrées, le jeu entre dans le "Chance time" pour 50 à 70 secondes. Score clignote sur et en dehors, en revenant la balle de Charlie Brown 5 points, la balle de Lucy marque 6 points. Le score maximal d'affichage est de 9999 points.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Snoopy Tennis-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Snoopy Tennis-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Snoopy Tennis-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19820428T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./Turtle Bridge.mgw</path>
		<name>Turtle Bridge</name>
		<desc>Votre personnage tente de convoyer des paquets de la rive gauche à la rive droite d'un lac en traversant sur le dos de tortues. Une fois la traversée effectuée, il retourne sur l'autre berge.
Quand une tortue voit un poisson remonter à la surface, elle plonge dans l'eau. Si votre personnage saute sur une tortue en plongée, c'est raté. La partie se termine après 3 échecs.
En mode de jeu A, la tortue du milieu ne plonge pas (sauf si le personnage reste trop longtemps sur son dos).
3 points sont attribués à chaque fois qu'un paquet est transmis et des points supplémentaires sont accordés au retour sur la berge d'en-face. Plus la traversée est rapide, plus le nombre de points augmente.
Lorsque le joueur atteint un score bonus, tous les échecs sont effacés en fanfare et le jeu continue. Si ce score bonus est atteint sans aucun échec, les tortues ne bougeront plus pendant quelques dizaines de secondes.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/Turtle Bridge-image.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/Turtle Bridge-marquee.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/Turtle Bridge-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19820201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_bfightn.zip</path>
		<name>Balloon Fight (New Wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Balloon Fight is a Crystal Screen and New Wide Screen Game &amp; Watch game released in 1986 (CS) and 1988 (NWS). The game is similar to the NES classic Balloon Fight, particularly its Balloon Trip mode. The model number for the Crystal Screen version is BF-803, while the model number for the New Wide Screen version is BF-107. The BF in the model numbers stands for Balloon Fight.
Like all the Game &amp; Watch units, it has a built-in clock, and it has an alarm as well. To set the alarm, use a pointed object and push the alarm switch. Once you do so, a character by the name of Sparky will come on the screen with a watering can. If he doesn't appear, then you must press the switch again. After this, you can adjust when the alarm will go off. When it does go off, an alarm will sound if you're not playing and Sparky will start to pour water out of his watering can. If you are playing, the alarm won't sound, but Sparky will still pour water out of the can. After the alarm goes off, it will continue to sound for a total of 20 seconds or until you press the time button.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bfightn_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bfightn.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bfightn.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_boxing.zip</path>
		<name>Boxing: Micro Vs. System </name>
		<desc>Boxing is a Micro VS. Game &amp; Watch game released in 1984 by Nintendo. In America, the game was originally known as Punch-Out!! (named after the popular franchise), though when the game was included in Game &amp; Watch Gallery 4 they changed the name back to Boxing. The model number for the game was BX-301. Within the box of the game were the unit, LR44 batteries, and a caution leaflet. In the game, you'll box another character. The game is seen from a 2D perspective, and your character is always on the right.

The only difference between Boxing and Punch-Out!! were the names and the box. The American box had artwork that was made specifically for it.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_boxing_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_boxing.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_boxing.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19840731T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Sport</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_bsweep.zip</path>
		<name>Bombsweeper</name>
		<desc>Bombsweeper was a multi-screen Game &amp; Watch video game released in June of 1987. The game was never released in Japan. The game's model number was BD-62.
	
	Dynamite Jack, a masked bomber, has planted many bombs in the sewers. You play the role of John Solver, who must descend into the sewer and defuse the bombs before it's too late!
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bsweep_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bsweep.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bsweep.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19870601T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_cgrab.zip</path>
		<name>Crab Grab</name>
		<desc>Crab Grab is a Super Color Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1984. It's model number is UD-202. In the game, crabs are moving towards your character. You must push them away and not let them pinch you. If three crabs pinch you, then it'll result in a game over, and you'll have to start over. There are four columns, each a different color (from left to right: purple, green, orange, and blue). The crabs will start to come from the top, and you'll have to move your character from left to right to push them away, though more and more will always come. The game was one of two Super Color games, the other being Spitball Sparky.

When Nintendo of America released the game, they made exclusive art for the box that wasn't present in the Japanese version. They also did this with Spitball Sparky and a couple of other titles. Within the game was a grey leaflet that told the gamer how to play. A similar leaflet was included in Spitball Sparky, though it was yellow instead of grey.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_cgrab_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_cgrab.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_cgrab.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19840221T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_chef.zip</path>
		<name>Chef</name>
		<desc>Chef is a wide-screen Game &amp; Watch game that was released in 1981. An estimated 1,000,000 units were manufactured by Nintendo. The game's model was FP-24, with the FP standing for Frying Pan. The contents within the game's box included the Game &amp; Watch unit, two LR43 batteries, battery stickers, and the game's instructions.

The original Game &amp; Watch game was released as a title in both Game &amp; Watch Gallery 2 and Game &amp; Watch Gallery 4. Enhanced versions were also included that featured Mario characters instead of the traditional ones that were present in the original. Chef also appears as a move Mr. Game &amp; Watch can perform in Super Smash Bros. Melee and Super Smash Bros. Brawl. After the player uses the kitchen timer in Personal Trainer: Cooking, Chef will become an unlockable game.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_chef_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_chef.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_chef.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19810908T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_climber.zip</path>
		<name>Climber (Crystal Screen)</name>
		<desc>Not to be confused with Ice Climber. Climber is a Game &amp; Watch video game released in the Crystal Screen format in 1986 and the New Wide Screen format in 1988. The game was never released in Japan, and an estimated 250,000 of the New Wide Screen version were produced by Nintendo. The model number for the Crystal Screen version is DR-802, while the model number for the New Wide Screen game is DR-106. Some speculate that the game is based on the Ice Climber NES game, though this is unconfirmed.

In Climber, you are a child known as Climber who, with the help of Lord Meiji's teachings, jumps across platforms trying to get to the top of Block Mountain while avoiding enemies and platforms that move. The enemies are the Blockmen, which walk and turn into block platforms when they reach a gap; Eyerom, birds that fly and get in the Climber's way; and thorny plants, which are obstacles in the way of Climber's movements. In each set of 5 levels, the first 4 ends with a bonus game where Climber has 2 chances to time his jump to catch Hentori, the bonus bird. On the fifth level, Climber must jump and grab the sword at the correct time to stab and defeat Dragalo the dragon.

Both versions of the game were essentially the same with only minor differences. There's a cheat in the game where if you press the jump button while also pressing the GAME button, you'll start the game at the sixth level.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_climber_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_climber.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_climber.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_climbern.zip</path>
		<name>Climber (New Wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Not to be confused with Ice Climber. Climber is a Game &amp; Watch video game released in the Crystal Screen format in 1986 and the New Wide Screen format in 1988. The game was never released in Japan, and an estimated 250,000 of the New Wide Screen version were produced by Nintendo. The model number for the Crystal Screen version is DR-802, while the model number for the New Wide Screen game is DR-106. Some speculate that the game is based on the Ice Climber NES game, though this is unconfirmed.

In Climber, you are a child known as Climber who, with the help of Lord Meiji's teachings, jumps across platforms trying to get to the top of Block Mountain while avoiding enemies and platforms that move. The enemies are the Blockmen, which walk and turn into block platforms when they reach a gap; Eyerom, birds that fly and get in the Climber's way; and thorny plants, which are obstacles in the way of Climber's movements. In each set of 5 levels, the first 4 ends with a bonus game where Climber has 2 chances to time his jump to catch Hentori, the bonus bird. On the fifth level, Climber must jump and grab the sword at the correct time to stab and defeat Dragalo the dragon.

Both versions of the game were essentially the same with only minor differences. There's a cheat in the game where if you press the jump button while also pressing the GAME button, you'll start the game at the sixth level.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_climbern_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_climbern.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_climbern.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_dkcirc.zip</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong Circus</name>
		<desc>Donkey Kong Circus is a Panorama Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1984. The game is an extremely rare title. The game is basically the same as Mickey Mouse on the Panorama, though instead of controlling Mickey you control Donkey Kong. In the game, Donkey Kong will juggle sticks, though when a torch comes you're required not to touch it or else you'll be burned.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkcirc_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkcirc.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkcirc.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19840901T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_dkhockey.zip</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong Hockey</name>
		<desc>Donkey Kong Hockey is a Micro VS. Game &amp; Watch game released in 1984 by Nintendo. Of the three Micro VS. Games, it was the last.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkhockey_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkhockey.png</marquee>
		<video />
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19841113T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Sport</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_dkjr.zip</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong Jr. (New Wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Donkey Kong Jr. is a New Wide Screen, Tabletop, and Panorama Game &amp; Watch game initially released in 1982. The Tabletop and Panorama versions are the same game, though the New Wide Screen version is different. The model numbers for the game are DJ-101, CJ-71, and CJ-93 for the New Wide Screen, Tabletop, and Panorama version, respectively. DJ stands for Donkey Kong Jr. while CJ stands for Color Jr. Nintendo manufactured 1,000,000 copies of the New Wide Screen version worldwide, though they only made 250,000 copies each of the other two.

As is the case with all the Game &amp; Watch games, all the three versions of the game feature a clock and an alarm. The clock's alarm can be set when the player pushes the switch button with a sharp object. If done correctly, a bell should appear on the screen in the New Wide Screen version, and in the Tabletop and Panorama version, musical notes will appear. After the time when the alarm is supposed to go off arrives, the alarm will sound (only if you aren't playing the game) and, in the New Wide Screen version Mario will arrive and strike the bell and in the other version, Mario will arrive and whistle the musical notes.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkjr_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkjr.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkjr.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830426T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_dkjrp.zip</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong Jr. (Panorama Screen)</name>
		<desc>Donkey Kong Jr. is a New Wide Screen, Tabletop, and Panorama Game &amp; Watch game initially released in 1982. The Tabletop and Panorama versions are the same game, though the New Wide Screen version is different. The model numbers for the game are DJ-101, CJ-71, and CJ-93 for the New Wide Screen, Tabletop, and Panorama version, respectively. DJ stands for Donkey Kong Jr. while CJ stands for Color Jr. Nintendo manufactured 1,000,000 copies of the New Wide Screen version worldwide, though they only made 250,000 copies each of the other two.

As is the case with all the Game &amp; Watch games, all the three versions of the game feature a clock and an alarm. The clock's alarm can be set when the player pushes the switch button with a sharp object. If done correctly, a bell should appear on the screen in the New Wide Screen version, and in the Tabletop and Panorama version, musical notes will appear. After the time when the alarm is supposed to go off arrives, the alarm will sound (only if you aren't playing the game) and, in the New Wide Screen version Mario will arrive and strike the bell and in the other version, Mario will arrive and whistle the musical notes.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkjrp_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkjrp.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkjrp.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830426T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_dkong.zip</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong</name>
		<desc>Donkey Kong is a Multi Screen Game &amp; Watch game released in 1982. It was based on the arcade game Donkey Kong, with gameplay based only on 25m, the first stage from the arcade version. This was the first Game and Watch game to be based on pre-existing Nintendo characters, and it was the first video game system to include the D-pad, a feature of all future Nintendo systems. The game unit's model is DK-52, with the DK standing for Donkey Kong. The game was a huge success, selling over 1,000,000 copies worldwide. The game comes with 2 LR44 batteries, which should last the player 6 months.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkong_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkong.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkong.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19820603T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_dkong2.zip</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong II</name>
		<desc>Donkey Kong II (ドンキーコングII) est un jeu d'action/plates-formes/puzzle sorti en 1983 sur Game &amp; Watch. C'est d'ailleurs la semi-suite de Donkey Kong Jr. et non la suite de Donkey Kong comme certains pourraient éventuellement le penser et malgré que certaines personnes le disent. Il a été réédité dans le jeu Mario, Game &amp; Watch Gallery 3. Alors que Donkey Kong Jr. sur Game &amp; Watch reprenait le premier niveau de la version arcade du jeu qui est la principale version, Donkey Kong II est plutôt inspiré du troisième et quatrième niveau de la version arcade de Donkey Kong Jr.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkong2_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkong2.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkong2.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830307T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action/Puzzle</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_dkong3.zip</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong III</name>
		<desc>Donkey Kong 3 is a Micro VS. Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1984 by Nintendo. It is one of three multiplayer Game &amp; Watch video games. The model number for Donkey Kong 3 is AK-302, with the AK standing for Attack Kong. The game, while bearing the same title, is entirely different from the arcade game Donkey Kong 3. In this game, one player will control Stanley, and the other will control Donkey Kong. Nintendo manufactured 250,000 units of the game worldwide.

As is the case with all Game &amp; Watch games, Donkey Kong 3 features a clock and an alarm. The alarm can be set when the player pushes a sharp object in the alarm switch. If done correctly, an image of a bell will appear on the screen. Once the time arrives, the bell will start moving, and the alarm will sound, the latter of which only occurring if the player isn't playing the game.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkong3_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkong3.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_dkong3.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19840820T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_egg.zip</path>
		<name>Egg</name>
		<desc>Egg is a Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1981. The game was similar to the previously released Mickey Mouse game, though due to copyright issues which prevented them from using the brand in some countries, they replaced Mickey Mouse with a wolf, though the gameplay remains essentially the same. The countries where Mickey Mouse was replaced by Egg include some Asian countries and Australia. In the Soviet Union there were the wolf and the hare from Soviet animated TV series Nu, Pogodi!. Egg was never released in Japan. Within the box were LR43 batteries, a caution leaflet, and battery stickers. The game sold an estimated 250,000 units worldwide. The game's model number is EG-26.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_egg_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_egg.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_egg.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19811009T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_fire.zip</path>
		<name>Fire (Wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Fire is a game where you control two firemen trying to bounce people falling from a burning building to an ambulance. This game was originally released in the Silver series on July 31, 1980. On December 4, 1981, the game was re-released as a part of the Wide Screen series.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_fire_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_fire.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_fire.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19811202T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_fires.zip</path>
		<name>Fire (Silver)</name>
		<desc>Fire is a game where you control two firemen trying to bounce people falling from a burning building to an ambulance. This game was originally released in the Silver series on July 31, 1980. On December 4, 1981, the game was re-released as a part of the Wide Screen series.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_fires_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_fires.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_fires.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19800731T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_fireatk.zip</path>
		<name>Fire Attack</name>
		<desc>The Game &amp; Watch game Fire Attack, released March 26, 1982, was a game where your character is a civil war-looking general, trying to defend his fort from an onslaught of Native Americans attacking with flaming torches.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_fireatk_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_fireatk.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_fireatk.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19820326T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_flagman.zip</path>
		<name>Flagman</name>
		<desc>Flagman is a game in the Game and Watch Silver Series released on May 6, 1980. It features a character holding up flags.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_flagman_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_flagman.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_flagman.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19800506T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_gcliff.zip</path>
		<name>Gold Cliff</name>
		<desc>Gold Cliff is a multi-screen Game &amp; Watch game about collecting treasure. The player controls an archaeologist and scales disappearing platforms in the ancient ruins. In every set of 4 levels, the first 3 require the player to grab a key on the right side of the ruins and take the key to the top left to progress. In the 4th level, the player must grab a sword on the left side of the ruins and take it to the top. At the top of the ruins, an enemy will be moving; to defeat it, the player must press up on the D-pad to stab the enemy when it is directly above. Each level is timed, and when the timer hits 30, crabs begin to appear, and will result in a miss if the touch the player.

Gold Cliff was released in 1988, making it the last Game &amp; Watch to be released before the Game Boy. This was the first Game and Watch to include a Continue button, which starts the player at the level they left off on the last time they played.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_gcliff_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_gcliff.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_gcliff.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19861001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_ghouse.zip</path>
		<name>Green House</name>
		<desc>Greenhouse is also referenced in the Super Smash Bros. series, as Mr. Game &amp; Watch's neutral attack, or jab. Green House is an attack used by Mr. Game &amp; Watch in which he uses a small pump and attacks with small puffs of gas which can be used repeatedly.

A microgame in the Nintendo DS video game WarioWare D.I.Y. is titled Greenhouse and is based on the Game &amp; Watch game.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_ghouse_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_ghouse.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_ghouse.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19821216T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_helmet.zip</path>
		<name>Helmet (CN-17 version)</name>
		<desc>Helmet is a game in the Gold series where you have to dodge tools and get to the door on the right. It was released on Febuary 21, 1981.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_helmet_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_helmet.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_helmet.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19810221T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_judge.zip</path>
		<name>Judge (green version)</name>
		<desc>Judge is a game in the Silver series released on October 4, 1980. Two versions of this game were released- a Green version, and a Purple version.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_judge_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_judge.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_judge.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19841004T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_lboat.zip</path>
		<name>Lifeboat</name>
		<desc>Lifeboat is a multi-screen Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1983. Nintendo produced an estimated 500,000 units worldwide. The model number for the game was TC-58. In the game, you'll have to maneuver two lifeboats and catch people who are jumping out of a ship on fire. The game was held similarly to how you would hold a book. Lifeboat was mentioned in the German magazine Telematch in 1984.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_lboat_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_lboat.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_lboat.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19831025T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_lion.zip</path>
		<name>Lion</name>
		<desc>The goal of the game is to keep the lions from escaping from their cages. Both zookeepers are controlled separately using the corresponding buttons. The lions will try to escape. To prevent them from doing so, position a zookeeper in front of the lion. The lions can also try to "fake-out" the player. Each time you prevent a lion from escaping, you score one point. The maximum score is 999. If a lion escapes, an animation will play of the zookeeper hiding in a tree, and you will get one miss. The game ends when you get three misses.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_lion_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_lion.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_lion.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19810101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_manhole.zip</path>
		<name>Manhole (New Wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Manhole is a game where you have to prevent pedestrians from falling into the water. It was first released on January 29, 1981, as a part of the Gold Series. It was later re-released as a part of the New Wide Screen series on August 24, 1983.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_manhole_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_manhole.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_manhole.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830824T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_manholeg.zip</path>
		<name>Manhole (Gold)</name>
		<desc>Manhole is a game where you have to prevent pedestrians from falling into the water. It was first released on January 29, 1981, as a part of the Gold Series. It was later re-released as a part of the New Wide Screen series on August 24, 1983.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_manholeg_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_manholeg.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_manholeg.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19810129T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_mario.zip</path>
		<name>Mario Bros.</name>
		<desc>Mario Bros. is a multi-screen Game &amp; Watch video game that stars Mario and Luigi. It marks the debut of Luigi. The Multi Screen unit is held sideways in a similar fashion to reading a book. The game was released in 1983 by Nintendo, and while it has the same name as Mario Bros. in the arcades, the game is not based on it, actually coming before the arcade version. Nintendo manufactured 1,000,000 units of the game worldwide. The game's model number is MW-56. The M stands for Mario, though it's unclear what the W stands for. Within the game's box were the game unit, two LR44 batteries, and instruction booklet and battery stickers.

As in all Game &amp; Watch games, Mario Bros. contains a clock that has an alarm. The alarm can be set by using a sharp object and pressing the alarm switch. If done correctly, an image of a bell should appear. Following this, you can set when the alarm should go off. Once the time arrives, an alarm will sound and the bell will start to move. If the player is playing the game, then the alarm will not sound, but the bell will still move. The alarm will continue to ring for about one minute.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mario_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mario.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mario.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830314T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_mariocm.zip</path>
		<name>Mario's Cement Factory (New Wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Mario's Cement Factory is a Game &amp; Watch video game released in both the Tabletop and New Wide Screen formats in 1983. The game starred, as the name suggests, Mario. For the New Wide Screen version, Nintendo produced an estimated 750,000 copies of the game. The amount that they made for the Tabletop version is unknown. The model number for the New Wide Screen version was ML-102, while the Tabletop's was CM-72. The model number for the Tabletop version of Mario's Cement Factory has caused some confusion, though it was revealed later than in a German magazine, an image of the game was shown and the logo read "Concrete Mixer", suggesting that the game was initially going to be called that, and explaining the model number. Within the New Wide Screen's version box was the actual game, LR44 batteries, a caution leaflet, and battery stickers.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariocm_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariocm.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariocm.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830616T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_mariocmt.zip</path>
		<name>Mario's Cement Factory (Table Top)</name>
		<desc>Mario's Cement Factory is a Game &amp; Watch video game released in both the Tabletop and New Wide Screen formats in 1983. The game starred, as the name suggests, Mario. For the New Wide Screen version, Nintendo produced an estimated 750,000 copies of the game. The amount that they made for the Tabletop version is unknown. The model number for the New Wide Screen version was ML-102, while the Tabletop's was CM-72. The model number for the Tabletop version of Mario's Cement Factory has caused some confusion, though it was revealed later than in a German magazine, an image of the game was shown and the logo read "Concrete Mixer", suggesting that the game was initially going to be called that, and explaining the model number. Within the New Wide Screen's version box was the actual game, LR44 batteries, a caution leaflet, and battery stickers.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariocmt_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariocmt.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariocmt.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830428T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_mariotj.zip</path>
		<name>Mario The Juggler</name>
		<desc>Mario the Juggler was the final Game &amp; Watch released on October 14, 1991. This is like a make of Ball but Mario juggling items. If he misses he gets made fun of by a Toad.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariotj_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariotj.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariotj.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19911014T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_mariotj.zip</path>
		<name>Mario The Juggler</name>
		<desc>Mario the Juggler was the final Game &amp; Watch released on October 14, 1991. This is like a make of Ball but Mario juggling items. If he misses he gets made fun of by a Toad.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariotj_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariotj.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mariotj.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19911014T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_mbaway.zip</path>
		<name>Mario's Bombs Away</name>
		<desc>Mario's Bombs Away is a game released as a Game &amp; Watch. The game consisted of moving a military-clad Mario from left to right and strategically placing bombs. As part of the Panorama screen series, the game was in color, and is played by watching a mirror in which the screen was reflected rather than by looking directly at the screen.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mbaway_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mbaway.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mbaway.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19831110T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_mickdon.zip</path>
		<name>Mickey &amp; Donald</name>
		<desc>Mickey &amp; Donald is a Multi Screen Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1982 by Nintendo. It stars the two Disney properties Mickey Mouse and Donald Duck. The game's model number is DM-53 (D standing for Donald and M standing for Mickey). The second release of the game didn't include the leaflet explaining to the player how to control the game. In the game, you'll control both of the characters whose goals are to extinguish fires.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mickdon_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mickdon.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mickdon.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19821112T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_mmouse.zip</path>
		<name>Mickey Mouse (Wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Mickey Mouse is two different Game &amp; Watch video games that first was released as a Wide Screen game in 1981. In 1984 there was a Panorama game released with the same name, but with completely different gameplay. The Wide screen issue was one of the better selling Game &amp; Watch video games with an astonishing 1,200,000 copies sold, and understandably so as it stars the popular Mickey Mouse character. It was developed by Nintendo and was released on October 9, 1981. The panorama issue is much rarer and highly sought after from collectors.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mmouse_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mmouse.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mmouse.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19811009T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_mmousep.zip</path>
		<name>Mickey Mouse (Panorama Screen)</name>
		<desc>Mickey Mouse is two different Game &amp; Watch video games that first was released as a Wide Screen game in 1981. In 1984 there was a Panorama game released with the same name, but with completely different gameplay. The Wide screen issue was one of the better selling Game &amp; Watch video games with an astonishing 1,200,000 copies sold, and understandably so as it stars the popular Mickey Mouse character. It was developed by Nintendo and was released on October 9, 1981. The panorama issue is much rarer and highly sought after from collectors.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mmousep_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mmousep.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_mmousep.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19840101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_octopus.zip</path>
		<name>Octopus</name>
		<desc>Octopus is a game in the Wide Screen series released on July 16, 1981. It features divers trying to get treasure.
	
	There are two buttons- one for moving the diver left/up, and one for moving right/down. The goal of the game is to collect treasure and return it to the boat. The Octopus' tentacles will try to grab the divers. If it grabs one, you lose one diver. The game ends when all three divers are grabbed by the Octopus.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_octopus_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_octopus.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_octopus.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19810716T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_opanic.zip</path>
		<name>Oil Panic</name>
		<desc>Oil Panic is a video game unit that was released as part of the Game &amp; Watch multi screen series. In the game, the player has to catch dripping oil from an oil leak in a pipe. Once he does, he has to go into his bosses room on the second screen to empty it. If he misses a drop then the player loses a life.
	
	Two customers are waiting at a gas station to fuel up. Meanwhile, an oil leak from a pipe on the third floor is causing confusion. Move Station Helper left and right by pressing the control buttons to catch the leaks in his bucket. Oil falls in drops. Helper's bucket holds three drops. Move Helper out to veranda to pour the oil in his bucket into the Boss's oil drum on the second floor. Be Careful not to drop oil on the waiting customers.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_opanic_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_opanic.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_opanic.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19820528T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_pchute.zip</path>
		<name>Parachute</name>
		<desc>Parachute is a game in the Wide Screen Series released on June 19, 1981. It features a man in a boat rescuing parachuting men.
	
	The goal of the game is to save the men parachuting from the helicopter. To do so, position the boat below the place where the men are parachuting towards. In Game B, sometimes men will get stuck on the palm tree to the right. For every man you save, you get one point. The maximum score is 999 points. If a man parachutes into the water, an animation plays of them getting chased by a shark, and you get one miss. The game ends when you get three misses.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_pchute_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_pchute.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_pchute.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19810619T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_popeye.zip</path>
		<name>Popeye (Wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Popeye is a Wide Screen Game &amp; Watch game released in 1981, under license from King Features Syndicate. The model code for this game is PP-23.

Gameplay: Players take control of Popeye The Sailor Man as he catches the things thrown by Olive Oyl. Missing 1 item is not a miss, but the 2nd time an item falls into the water, or Popeye is hit by Bluto's attacks counts as a miss. The game ends when the player gets 3 misses. In Game A, Bluto will try to hit Popeye with a hammer on the left, but in Game B, not only will Bluto try to hit Popeye with a hammer on the left, he will also try to punch him on the right, and will still count as a miss if Popeye gets punched. Olive Oyl swings a bell when the alarm goes off.

Trivia: Popeye was also released for the Tabletop and Panorama Game &amp; Watch games, but those are different then the Wide Screen version. The alarm tone is also used in Helmet, Octopus, Parachute, and the Wide Screen re-release of Fire.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_popeye_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_popeye.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_popeye.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19810101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_popeyep.zip</path>
		<name>Popeye (Panorama Screen)</name>
		<desc>Unlike its predecessor, the newer game employs color graphics over a black background. An entirely different game, it focuses on Popeye fighting Brutus to rescue the kidnapped Olive. Both opponents stand face-to-face on a pier and throw punches at each other, with the hero controlled by moving left and right and using a punch button. Popeye has to force his enemy towards the left by attacking him until he falls into the water, doing this three times in a row will make spinach available and result in Olive's rescue. If Popeye were to fall from the right edge, he would lose a life. Losing all three results in a game over. Also, in the harder setting, a swordfish will appear that may stab Popeye trough the pier and push him closer to the edge.

This game was released in two versions: a handheld "Panorama Screen" unit, and a "Table Top" version that stood upright and resembled a miniature arcade cabinet, complete with a small joystick used for the side-to-side movement.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_popeyep_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_popeyep.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_popeyep.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_rshower.zip</path>
		<name>Rain Shower</name>
		<desc>Rain Shower is a multiscreen Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1983. It was released in 1983 and Nintendo reportedly made an estimated 250,000 units worldwide. In the game, your clothes are hanging up to dry outside, but it's about to rain, and you have to make sure your clothes don't get wet. The rain comes down in segments, so you can move the wire from left to right to make sure the segment of rain that's coming down don't get onto your clothes.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_rshower_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_rshower.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_rshower.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_sbuster.zip</path>
		<name>Safe Buster</name>
		<desc>Safebuster is a multi-screen Game &amp; Watch game released in January of 1988. The game was never released in Japan. The game's model number was JB-63. Worldwide Nintendo manufactured an estimated 500,000 Safebuster models. A pocket size version of Safebuster was also released in America and Europe. 
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_sbuster_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_sbuster.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_sbuster.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19880112T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_smbn.zip</path>
		<name>Super Mario Bros. (New Wide Screen)</name>
		<desc>Super Mario Bros. for the Game &amp; Watch was a game that was released on the Crystal Screen and New Wide Screen unit. While the exact date of its release is unknown, it can be confirmed that it was released sometime in June of 1986 and March of 1988. A special edition of the game, which came with a winner certificate, a license card, and battery cover stickers, and a copy of the game in a Diskun-shaped case was given away in August of 1987.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_smbn_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_smbn.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_smbn.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19880308T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_snoopyp.zip</path>
		<name>Snoopy (Panorama Screen)</name>
		<desc>Snoopy for the Game &amp; Watch was a game that was released on the Panorama Screen unit in 1983.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_snoopyp_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_snoopyp.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_snoopyp.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19830101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_squish.zip</path>
		<name>Squish</name>
		<desc>Squish is a Multi Screen Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1986 by Nintendo. The game was never released in Japan. A Pocketsize version of the game was also released. The unit's model number was MG-61. In the game, you have to avoid the platforms that are coming towards the player character, Ziggy the Mazeman. The game's name comes from the fact that you'll be "squished" if a platform hits you. The top screen contained game information, while all of the action took place on the bottom screen. This and Zelda were the only two games to have a format like this when it came to multi-screen games.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_squish_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_squish.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_squish.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19860401T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_ssparky.zip</path>
		<name>Spitball Sparky</name>
		<desc>Spitball Sparky is a Super Color Game &amp; Watch game released in 1984 by Nintendo. The game's model number was BU-201, and the contents within the box included the game, LR44 batteries, a caution leaflet, a how to play leaflet, and battery stickers. The game is very similar to the arcade classic Arcanoid and has colors due to the layers of colored plastic overlay. Your goal is to spit on the ball so that it'll go back up and destroy the blocks at the top. The unit was rectangular and silver. When Nintendo of America released the game in America, they made artwork for the game that had a more detailed character.

Interestingly when Nintendo was manufacturing the game, a few of the units came out white instead of the regular silver color. Nintendo didn't notice the mistake and released the game. Today the white version of Spitball Sparky is extremely rare and is a collector's item. In the May of 1984 issue of German magazine Telematch, there was information contained within regarding Spitball Sparky, one of the few if not only appearance of the game in print.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_ssparky_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_ssparky.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_ssparky.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19840207T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_tbridge.zip</path>
		<name>Turtle Bridge</name>
		<desc>Turtle Bridge is a widescreen Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1982 by Nintendo. In the game, you must get the character from one side of a lake to the other by jumping on the shells of turtles that are protruding from the water. If you jump on a turtle at the wrong time, then you will have to go back to the beginning. The fact that the turtles gain your character access to the other side of the lake is where the game's name originates from.

Contents within the game box include the Game &amp; Watch unit, LR43 batteries, a caution leaflet, battery stickers, and, in the first edition of the game, an error leaflet which cautioned players of an error in the game's instruction booklet which was later corrected in future versions. The model number for the game was TL-28. The game sold an estimated 500,000 units worldwide. It is currently unknown if a pocket-sized version was ever released. There is an estimated 200 to 500 Bosch versions of the game, which were only released through promotions.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_tbridge_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_tbridge.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_tbridge.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19820201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_tfish.zip</path>
		<name>Tropical Fish</name>
		<desc>Tropical Fish is a rare New Wide Screen Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1985. The game was never released in Japan. The model number for Tropical Fish is TF-104. In the game, you'll merge fish from an aquarium into another aquarium via a fishbowl. Overall, the gameplay is very similar to Fire, though perhaps slightly improved. Tropical Fish has also appeared as an unlockable museum game in Game &amp; Watch Gallery 4, albeit in Classic only.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_tfish_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_tfish.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_tfish.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19850701T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_vermin.zip</path>
		<name>Vermin</name>
		<desc>Vermin is a game in the Game and Watch Silver Series released on July 10, 1980. In the game, you play as a character with two hammers trying to get rid of moles.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_vermin_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_vermin.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_vermin.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19800710T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./gnw_zelda.zip</path>
		<name>Zelda</name>
		<desc>Game &amp; Watch: Zelda (serial number ZL-65) is a handheld LCD game developed by Gunpei Yokoi and Nintendo R&amp;D1 and released in August 1989 in North America, as part of Nintendo's Game &amp; Watch Multi Screen series. It is the first handheld Zelda title, coming out four years before The Legend of Zelda: Link's Awakening. Similar to other Multi Screen games, it has two screens with a hinge in the center and the buttons on the bottom half, making it look strikingly similar to the Nintendo DS. It is a side-scrolling action game, and the gameplay and items are inspired by Zelda II: The Adventure of Link.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_zelda_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_zelda.png</marquee>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_zelda.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19890826T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game id="88095" source="ScreenScraper">
		<path>./bassmate.zip</path>
		<name>Bassmate Computer</name>
		<desc>The Bassmate I saw was sold under the name of a brand called "Probe 2000" and dated from 1984. At first glance, it seemed like a regular sporting aid, be it one that was quite advanced for its time.

However, when checking out the image on the back of the box, something dawned on me. That shape seemed rather familiar! It looked just like a Game &amp; Watch Multi Screen!

When taking a closer look, it appeared that everything matched; the overall design of the case, the hinges, the connector between the bottom and top part, the shape of the buttons - they all looked like they came straight out of the kitchen of the handheld master from Kyoto.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/bassmate_system.png</image>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/bassmate.png</marquee>
		<video />
		<thumbnail />
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19840101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gnw_pinball.zip</path>
		<name>Pinball</name>
		<desc>Pinball is a Multi Screen Game &amp; Watch game released in December of 1983. Nintendo manufactured around 250,000 units of the game worldwide. It's basically just a portable pinball game where you control two flippers. The goal is to keep the ball above the flippers by hitting it. The ball will then go in a fairly random direction and hit the bumpers, thus giving the player points. The model number for the game was PB-59, with PB standing for Pinball. The game's box came with the unit, two LR44 batteries, an instruction booklet and battery stickers.

As is the case with all Game &amp; Watch games, Pinball has a clock with an alarm. If you wish to set the alarm, then you should use a sharp object and push the switch. If done correctly, a bell will appear. The bell is the game's alarm icon. Following this, you can set the time for when the alarm will sound. Once the time arrives, the bell will start to move and flash while the alarm will sound. If you're playing the game, the bell will still move around, though the alarm will not sound.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_pinball_system.png</image>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_pinball.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_pinball.png</marquee>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19831105T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20201106T024604</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gnw_stennis.zip</path>
		<name>Snoopy Tennis</name>
		<desc>Snoopy Tennis is a Game &amp; Watch video game released in 1982 by Nintendo. The game was very successful, perhaps due to the Snoopy label, with Nintendo producing an estimated 1,200,000 worldwide. In the game, you control Snoopy, moving him up and down to make him hit the oncoming tennis balls with your racket. It was released on the Wide Screen format. A version of the game was released as a keychain title under the mini-classics label. The control button leaflet, which was only present in this game's box and Fire Attack's, showcases various characters from the Peanuts franchise. Unsurprisingly, due to licensing issues, the game was not released in any of the Game &amp; Watch video games, though it was mentioned in Super Smash Bros. Brawl for the Wii.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_stennis_system.png</image>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_stennis.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_stennis.png</marquee>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19820428T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20201106T024644</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gnw_smb.zip</path>
		<name>Super Mario Bros. (Crystal Screen)</name>
		<desc>Super Mario Bros. for the Game &amp; Watch was a game that was released on the Crystal Screen and New Wide Screen unit. While the exact date of its release is unknown, it can be confirmed that it was released sometime in June of 1986 and March of 1988. A special edition of the game, which came with a winner certificate, a license card, and battery cover stickers, and a copy of the game in a Diskun-shaped case was given away in August of 1987.
	</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_smb_system.png</image>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_smb.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_smb.png</marquee>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19860625T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20201106T024717</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gnw_ball.zip</path>
		<name>Ball</name>
		<desc>Ball est le premier jeu de la gamme de jeux électroniques Game and Watch créée par Nintendo. Il appartient à la série Silver. Le joueur contrôle les bras d'un personnage (Mr. Game and Watch) dans le but de rattraper des balles qui tombent et donc de jongler. Il y a deux modes de jeu : "game A", dans lequel le joueur jongle avec deux balles et "game B" où il jongle avec trois balles. Il n'y a que deux boutons d'action : gauche et droite. Comme sur n'importe quel Game and Watch, il est possible de lire l'heure.</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_ball_system.png</image>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_ball.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_ball.png</marquee>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19800428T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20201106T134503</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gnw_bfight.zip</path>
		<name>Balloon Fight (Crystal Screen)</name>
		<desc>Balloon Fight is a Crystal Screen and New Wide Screen Game &amp; Watch game released in 1986 (CS) and 1988 (NWS). The game is similar to the NES classic Balloon Fight, particularly its Balloon Trip mode. The model number for the Crystal Screen version is BF-803, while the model number for the New Wide Screen version is BF-107. The BF in the model numbers stands for Balloon Fight.
Like all the Game &amp; Watch units, it has a built-in clock, and it has an alarm as well. To set the alarm, use a pointed object and push the alarm switch. Once you do so, a character by the name of Sparky will come on the screen with a watering can. If he doesn't appear, then you must press the switch again. After this, you can adjust when the alarm will go off. When it does go off, an alarm will sound if you're not playing and Sparky will start to pour water out of his watering can. If you are playing, the alarm won't sound, but Sparky will still pour water out of the can. After the alarm goes off, it will continue to sound for a total of 20 seconds or until you press the time button.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bfight_system.png</image>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bfight.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bfight.png</marquee>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20201107T031150</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gnw_bjack.zip</path>
		<name>Black Jack</name>
		<desc>Black Jack is a Multi Screen Game &amp; Watch game released in 1985 by Nintendo. A Pocketsize version was also released. The model number for the game was BJ-60 (BJ obviously standing for Black Jack). The contents within the box include the Game &amp; Watch unit, LR44 batteries, a caution leaflet, a ball/score leaflet, and battery stickers. For some reason, there are some Black Jack games that were included in white boxes that Nintendo sent out to retailers. The reason for the white box is unknown, though it's also been confirmed that Donkey Kong 2 and Super Mario Bros. featured similar boxes.

The game is simply Black Jack on an LCD screen. The game is very different from the standard Game &amp; Watch games. If your cards amount to a combined number of 21, then you win the game. Black Jack is the last Game &amp; Watch video games to be released in Japan. All games released after Black Jack were released only in other countries, despite being made in Japan.
</desc>
		<image>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bjack_system.png</image>
		<video>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bjack.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./media/emulationstation/gnw_bjack.png</marquee>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19850101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Casino</genre>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20201107T214902</lastplayed>
	</game>
</gameList>
